In this video, I'm going to be helping
one random business create SEO content
that ranks everywhere. So, let's begin
with the most important part, which is
defining what SEO content actually is.
So, very simply, what is SEO content?
The way that I personally define this is
any asset built around a specific topic
that your ideal client profile is likely
to search. And so a lot of people will
think that these are pages or posts on a
website that is a type of SEO content.
But if we change the definition of SEO
to search everywhere optimization, then
that starts to change the dynamics a
little bit. And so we're looking at our
website and we're looking at our pages
and our posts, but then we're also
looking at videos. We're looking at
social content. Anything that search
engines will index can be used as SEO
content. That is the goal. We're trying
to dominate search across as many
surfaces as possible. And the outcome of
this, when you do this well, you can
rank everywhere. And so, here's a little
quick example for a keyword that we're
targeting in our business. And you can
see we've taken over the actual getting
recommended in the AI overview. We've
got the primary citation in the AI
overview. We're ranking number one in
traditional search. And then we've taken
over that video pack as well. So, this
is what you want to see. And then of
course if you look across chat GBT and
Perplexi and all the other AI platforms
are also doing well there as well. But
the point is this is what you want to
focus on. You really want to focus on
topic domination. And so today what I'm
going to be showing you is obviously I'm
going to show you how to improve a
single page. But the reality of this is
if you want to really achieve this goal
of creating SEO content that ranks
everywhere, you have to truly attack
many different parts of the SEO process.
So let's dive right in. So, the
particular business that we're looking
at here today is a roofing company. So,
I just picked roofer in Chesterfield,
Missouri. Found a page that was not
ranking particularly well, and we're
going to go ahead and take a look at
them. So, we'll go ahead and just take a
quick look at the site. So, we're going
to dig into a couple key elements here,
but let's just start with the most
obvious part is just how is this page
performing in Chesterfield. Now, if you
want to focus on this concept of search
everywhere optimization, then you need
to actually run an analysis to see how
well they're doing across every search
surface. So, what we're going to look at
here is we're first going to go to
traditional search and see if they're
showing up at all. Okay, so right away
we see they're not showing up in
traditional search across any search
engine. Okay, Google, Bing, Duck.Go,
Brave, they're not there. So, already
got some work to do on that front. Then
we've got the AI answers. Is their brand
being recommended by these AI platforms?
The short answer is no. So once again,
another thing that we're going to have
to work on. And then are they being used
in retrieval? Are they one of the core
citation sources? The short answer is
no. Okay. And then just for fun, we can
go and look at video search and see, are
they showing up in YouTube video search?
Are they showing up in Google's video
pack? Now, usually you're not going to
see a video pack for local queries, but
still something worth looking into. And
then even looking at Tik Tok, are their
videos showing up on Tik Tok. Are their
Tik Tok videos recommending their
particular brand? And the answer is no.
So, what we end up with here is
unfortunately a goose egg, which is just
a zero. This is good news and bad news.
The bad news is we're obviously missing
out on opportunities to grow our
business. But the other benefit of this
is it's easy to go from zero to at least
more visible, right? This is as low as
it goes. So it's only up from here. So
this is actually a really good thing. So
we've established our benchmarks. Now
what's the next step in this process?
All right. So we've got current
performance. So mark these off. You know
what SEO is. So now we're going to do on
page SEO 101. So let's take a look at
this page. And at a very basic level,
what you want to see is the primary
topic showing up in the most important
parts on the page. So at a bare minimum,
we want to see that it's showing up in
the URL. So we see here roofing
contractor in Chesterfield MO. This
actually is a pass. So this is good.
We've got roofing. We've got
Chesterfield, Missouri. So you it
doesn't need to be the exact query
because the LLM are so good at this that
they will make this is basically the
same thing. It's synonymous. Okay. So,
it used to be many years ago, you would
have to kind of go after each single
variant. The AI is so smart these days,
it doesn't need to do that. So, just at
least get the primary topic and the URL.
You'll be good to go. There's no
advantage to getting super super
specific or changing this even. So, I
would keep this the same. Next one I
want to look at is the primary topic in
the title tag. So, when we look at this,
we see roofing once again is appearing.
So, that topic and that entity is
appearing in the title. So, that's good.
We see Chesterfield once again appearing
in the title. So those two entities are
appearing. That's exactly what we want
to see. The only thing I would say here
is to add M O because Missouri is an
entity and you want to make sure that
it's clear that this is in Missouri.
There are other Chesterfields across the
United States. So you want to make it
really clear to these systems that this
is Chesterfield, Missouri. So you got
both of those entities, the city entity
and the state entity together. Okay. So,
we've got title, tag, looks good, metad
description, URL, all good to go. So,
then we'll look at the headings. They
are definitely optimized. We'll be
talking about that here in a second, but
they are definitely optimized. They've
got they're putting that primary topic
in there a lot. So, we're going to talk
about how to improve this though. Okay.
So, on page SEO 101, they're pretty
solid. They've gotten the H1 tag.
They've got it across many headings.
They've got it all over the page.
They're doing that well. This is a
situation where there's a lot of things
that we need to work on. So, a couple
things. Number one, the most important
thing, yes, I can look at this page and
see that it's clearly AI content and
there's lots of other things going on,
but there's a bigger glaring issue that
really stands out to me, which is this
page does not satisfy the intent
correctly. Okay, so what does that mean?
It means that whenever you build a page
on your website, it needs to have a
[snorts] clear focus. Every page must
have a singular focus, not multiple
focuses, one focus. And so what we're
seeing here is we've got roofing
solutions for Chesterfield homes, retail
centers, and commercial properties.
Okay, those are three different types of
intent, different ideal client profiles,
different buyers. So, we don't want to
combine that all together. That's really
hard. Not even from an SEO perspective.
Just from a pure sales perspective,
imagine trying to sell to those three
different ideal client profiles all on
one page. That's really hard and it's
not going to be an effective message
whatsoever. So, it's very clear that
this page, whoever built this strategy,
the attempt here was just to try to
dominate as many topics as possible on
one singular page without having to
spread this across. can work sometimes.
But the thing is, even if it does work,
this page is not going to perform
particularly well from a conversion
perspective. So yes, you may possibly
win just by pure SEO objectives, but you
lose on the conversion side because the
page is not built to convert. So always
begin with the conversion. Always begin
with that first and then SEO comes
second. So in this case, when I look at
this page, I just see it needs to be
rebuilt completely from scratch. I would
never try to optimize a page like this.
I would just say throw it in the trash,
start over. And so in this case, what I
would do is I would focus in on roofing,
Chesterfield, Missouri. So the entire
theme of this page will be built around
that core topic. Okay? And we're not
going to if we talk about retail centers
or commercial properties, that's going
to actually be a secondary topic that
we're going to build internal links to
dedicated pages for those topics that
need to live. Right? So, we've got our
dedicated roofing page, which is, let's
call it our pillar page. Then, we've got
our dedicated page that's specifically
for roofing for retail centers in
Chesterfield. And then we've got another
one for which is roofing for commercial
properties in Chesterfield. Just by
looking at the heading, we already see
three different pages that have to be
built. Okay. So when we look at this
very clearly, another thing here is in
addition to just being not focused
around a one core pillar, one core
topic, the page itself, the design, the
structure is not built to match the
intent. Okay? So when someone is
searching for a roofer in Chesterville,
Missouri, they have no interest in
reading this much content. This content
is not built to convert. This is just
slapped on the site. And then this just
this type of structure doesn't even
satisfy the intent. This should be a
conversiondriven page and I'll be
showing you what that looks like here in
a second. But this is not what you want
to see on top of it. When we look at
this, even we you clearly all AI
content. I don't even need to run it
through any checker. But when we run
this here, look at this little section.
This has no utility for someone that's
looking for a roofer in Chesterfield,
Missouri. You live in Chesterfield.
You're searching for a roofer. What
would this matter to someone who's
trying to get fix their roof in
Chesterfield, Missouri? they already
probably live in Chesterfield, Missouri.
Therefore, they don't need to know some
some generic information about
Chesterfield. So, even the content
strategy here is incorrect. And once
again, showing that you can use AI
content, but you can still use AI
content incorrectly.
Just because you've got a good tool
doesn't mean you know how to use that
tool well. And I see this all the time.
And so, we're going to refine this
strategy. We're going to make this page
better. We're going to ultimately build
a page that's going to be built not just
to rank, but built to convert. Okay, so
that's the other part of the kind of
irrelevant content, a lot of fluff, a
lot of kind of junky stuff, extremely
overoptimized,
not built for conversions, not built to
match the intent. And then on top of it,
this is clearly not even a page. They
actually posted this in their blog
section. And the way I know that without
even needing to dig into is we see these
recent posts. If this is on WordPress,
then these recent posts are
automatically generated in the blog
section. And then we scroll down, you'll
be able to see more related posts. So
this is clearly in the blog. It is not a
dedicated page. It should be a page. If
you're using WordPress, it should have
that structure. Now, let me make one
thing clear here. The search engines and
AI platforms do not care whether it's a
page or a post, right? That doesn't make
a difference. But it's more for the
structure of how this should be set. If
you're going to build a custom landing
page, it should be a landing page. It
should not be in the structure of a blog
post because it doesn't even fulfill the
intent correctly. Okay, so I think I've
made my point clear about this that we
got to rebuild from scratch. Okay, so
that's the first part. So that's the
initial assessment. Now, one thing I'm
going to do is do a quick a quick
assessment of topic coverage. Now, let's
say I wasn't going to rebuild this page
from scratch. I would go ahead and run
it through a tool and see how well is it
covering the core topics. Okay, so we'll
put this over here. And so basically
this is this extracted all of the
content from that page looking at roofer
Chesterfield, Missouri and then seeing
how well they're covering the topic
relative to the top competitors for this
topic. So, what we see here is even with
all that kind of I hate to say it like
spammy stuff, you can see it's still not
actually covering a lot of the core
topics that need to be covered. Like we
see metal roofing, metal roofing, you
can see tile roofing, slate, shingle, so
on and so forth. There's all kind of
topics in here that that need to be
covered on this page that are completely
neglected in this page because it's very
clear that the intent here was to just
try to focus on jamming the city as much
as possible in here and keeping it
relatively basic. So once again, even a
page that is purely let's use AI to go
hard here still isn't covering the topic
the way that it should and they're
missing out on so many opportunities to
build relevance. 44 topics that are
definitely relevant to this core topic.
Okay, so that's the next thing I'd be
doing is if I was going to let's say I
wasn't going to tear this thing down and
build it from scratch, I'd be looking at
these unused topics and think about how
can I integrate these topics naturally
into this page. Okay. So, but with that
in mind, let's keep going here. So,
we've got topic coverage for the page
level. Then what we want to look at is
the topic coverage on the site level.
So, just go into Google. The simplest
thing you can do is just run a very
simple site search and just put the
primary city in there. And we can see
that they don't really cover
Chesterfield anywhere else, right? And
there's no other pages targeting
Chesterfield. They have basically just
one page for Chesterfield, Missouri.
That is not going to work. You're not
going to be able to compete against
roofers that only service Chesterfield,
Missouri, or they have an address in
Chesterfield, Missouri. There's
absolutely no way that you'll be able to
beat them unless you go absolutely crazy
with building topic support around
Chesterfield. But I'm saying in this
case, this is not going to be a local
pack game because this business doesn't
have a Google business profile in
Chesterfield, Missouri. If they wanted
to truly dominate this query, they would
need to go and get an address in
Chesterfield. They would need to have a
Google business profile in Chesterfield.
But if they're not willing to do that,
then the next strategy we have to deploy
would be purely an organic strategy
outside the local pack, which is what
I'm going to be focusing on here. Okay.
So now we've got the topic authority
check. And then the last one here is
just a quick site quality assessment. So
what I did is I ran a quick little
domain level audit. And you'll be able
to see this. So, this is just a standard
audit you can run. I don't have any of
their data, so I can't go super crazy on
this, but the one thing I want to show
you is when we look at duplicate content
specifically. Okay, so you click on this
and you can see that this is just a
classic situation on the local level.
Unfortunately, when there's just this
kind of boilerplate cookie cutter type
of pages that are being built out with
an attempt to manipulate coverage across
many different cities, it just doesn't
work that well. I'm just going to be
totally frank. It just doesn't work. And
you would be better off not creating all
these pages. Pick one city, just
Chesterfield, and spend all your time
building good pages in that one cluster.
That is it. You focus on one cluster at
a time. Ignore everything else. Once you
have satisfied that cluster, then move
on to the next one. But this is here.
It's like you're going literally one
little centimeter across every entity.
You're never going to you're never going
to beat a business that just focuses on
that one location. So, we can see we can
click on one of these and see very
clearly it's basically the same exact
content used across every single page.
Okay, it's all the same stuff basically
83% match. Okay, and this is just across
we can see here 41 pages share basically
almost the same exact content. So, once
again, I'm trying to keep this scope so
I don't go across the whole website. But
if if this was a site I was working on,
there would be a lot of deconstruction
of this website. Lots. We would be
deleting. We'd be pruning. We'd be
consolidating. We'd be redirecting. I
wouldn't be messing with making the
pages better yet. I would just be
completely being ruthless about wiping a
lot of these pages out and starting from
scratch. You're actually better off to
do that because most of this is dragging
the site down. Okay, so we've got that
covered now. So, we got the site quality
assessment. We're good to go. audit is
pretty clean on the page level. All
right. So, as I mentioned, we're doing a
pure organic strategy, no local pack.
So, what are we going to do? I'm going
to rebuild that content from scratch.
So, very simply, I've already built out
some a very brief draft here. Now,
normally the way we would do this is we
would run multiple iterations on this
the copy first. So, this is just the
very first draft. And basically, I took
their information from their website,
from their about page and stuff like
that, and I built it into the draft. So
you can see here it's very relevant to
what they do. And you can see once again
if we compare just this. So we'll
compare this to this post here. All
right. Look at the difference. Okay. So
you'll see this one here. So we're
pretty much the same on this front. It's
this is proper commercial intent for the
most part. But it's as soon as we get
down here where things start to change.
Now you look at the difference. Okay.
We'll compare these. This is
veryformational
generic kind of stuff. This is built to
convert. Okay, we'll just look at an
HTML handoff here and you'll see the
difference in these pages. Okay, so this
is just creates a little wireframe here,
but you can see once again this is what
a proper above the fold would look like.
This is what kind of a new section for a
commercial page would look like. So you
can see it's starting to break down into
specific sections for the proper
wireframe for a commercial page or a
service page on the local level. Okay,
so we've got the services, we've got the
trust bar, we've got the why why you
should pick this particular business.
You've got results and social proof, you
got testimonials, how it works, these
the area that they service, and then
frequently asked questions. Now, one
thing I want to tell you, this is
something that's cool, is we actually
reverse engineered, man, it was like
many thousands of local service pages
that are proven that have proven
visibility across Google and the AI
platforms. So this template you see
here, this is the exact template that's
proven to work. This is not made up.
This is this is proven to work across
many different industries, many
different local areas across the board.
It's it is that effective. So basically
that's the way when this the tool
produces this particular type of
content, it is based on reality, based
on what actually works. But the bigger
picture here, the most important part of
this is that it's actually matching the
intent. This is what makes the
difference, okay? Because when you match
the intent, you can take this page and
it's going to be a very easy handoff to
hand this off to your designer. It's
going to be a very easy handoff for the
designer to hand this off to the
developer. Okay. Now, fortunately, AI
has made life a lot easier on that
front, that handoff, because it used to
be you'd have to take this content and
actually go and find a designer to build
this page. Typically, designing one page
can be anywhere between And depending on
the extreme quality, it could be
anywhere between $50 to $1,000 for one
page. That does happen depending on the
level of seniority you're going to be
using as far as that designer. Now, what
I personally do to create my mockups is
I just go into clawed design. Okay? So,
I'll show you an example here. So, we
got the copy. We're good to go. Like I
said, this copy would go through at
least two to three, sometimes four
iterations before getting to this next
stage. Just keep that in mind. But for
the sake of this video, we'll just move
into the next part. Okay. So, the
wireframe and the design. So, what
you're looking at here, this is similar
to what you would see with the
wireframe. Very basic kind of thing. But
truthfully, what I do is I just go in
here because AI is so good. I just go
and I export as markdown. Okay. Export
as markdown. And then I'm going to go
over to Claude. And you're going to see
that what I did. I'll actually open up
the chat here so you can see. So, we'll
go to the very top. And you can see that
I told it to extract the color scheme
and then build a conversion focus design
for the specific topic. I attached the
copy that's from the markdown. And then
I told it to create three unique
variants. This does cost more tokens to
run three unique variants. But I just
personally like seeing different
especially if you're working with
clients. You want to make sure that
you're giving them multiple options.
Design can be pretty tricky when working
with clients because everyone's got it's
very subjective in nature. So you want
to try to give multiple options and that
way eventually maybe you can agree on
them and then from there what I did here
is I used Claude to basically build some
prototypes and so you can see if we look
at this page look at the difference and
by the way I didn't design this I just
took the copy and then built out these
wireframes. So you look at this one
compared to what we see over here. Okay
so this is the difference big block of
text not super helpful not going to
drive any conversions. Now, here's the
part that's cool is you look at this is
one thing that AI is so good at now.
It's just crazy. So, you can look at the
copy here. Okay, so look at this raw
copy. Okay, now sometimes when you work
with designer developer, they have a
hard time kind of how do I fit this into
the page? And so, honestly, the AI is
just so good at it. So, you can see even
though this is not giving any
instructions, I fed this into the AI and
it was smart enough to know to put it it
just in the right spots. Look at this.
since 2012. It'll put it right there.
Boom. Perfect placement. You can see
here covering the topic. You can see
here familyowned. There's a bunch of
stuff in here about being familyowned
over here. Right here. So, you can see
it's it's putting everything in a
perfect spot. And it's not, by the way,
once again, just like the copy is going
to go through three, four iterations,
this page is going to go for go through
three to four iterations before it goes
live. But the fact that this is one shot
with just some markdown coffee and this
is what we get is unbelievable, right?
And we look at this, you can see that
the trust bar, the uh assessment part,
what they do as far as the services. You
can see the services overview, very
simple copy that covers the topic, but
then it puts it in a beautiful format.
And then we go over here once again,
just building out the structure that it
needs to be. This is proper structure
for a service page. This is exactly what
you want to see. Okay. And once again,
clawed. So, what I do, like I mentioned,
is I like to get three different
prototypes. So, this is like prototype
number one. This one's a little more
what I would call riskier. I would not
propose this to a client, but I still
like to just see what it can do. And
then this one here's a little bit, it's
like a variant of the original one. I
still think the first one is probably
the best one. This one looks the nicest
in my opinion. Of course, it's very
subjective, but this one looks really
nice. Okay, so just very quickly this
was like five minutes of work. I just
created the copy and then I put it into
cloud design and built out three
prototypes. The real work though, I want
to make this very clear. This is the
easy part. The real work begins with a
when you've when you've built out these
prototypes. The magic of getting AI to
be very effective is in the editing.
This is the part where most people mess
up. Anyone can do what I just did. But
the real magic happens when I look at
this page and I start to play with it
and tweak it and edit it and improve it.
Same thing with the content. That's
where the magic happens. This initial
generation, this initial prototypes as
far as content, as far as design, this I
don't see why you would be doing this
from scratch these days. It would just
it seems crazy to me given where we are
now. Okay, so that's what I'm saying is
we can do this very fast. We can see
significant improvements across the
board as far as copy, as far as design.
It's pretty unbelievable. Okay, so next
part is we got the full rebuild. Pretty
good on that. Now, the next piece of
this is once you've published that page,
now you've got a beautiful conversion
focused design that's that's covering
all the topics. It's built to rank
across every single AI platform. What's
the next step? The next step is if you
just publish this page, you really
haven't changed anything that was
already being done, right? So going back
to the this section here looking at
topic authority. Even if we just improve
this page, yeah, we made the page
better, but we didn't make any progress
really because we still don't have
enough topic support to win anyway. So
you could build the perfect page,
perfect relevance, per build to convert,
like everything I've talked about today,
but if you haven't built support around
it, you're still not going to win.
You're just not going to win. So what do
you do? What I do personally is I go
back to that report here, that's
actually the existing report. So what I
go back to on this one is I will just
download this CSV. Okay, download the
CSV and then I will go into the AI over
here and I will upload that CSV. Okay,
so I'll upload the CSV and then I'll say
I need you to build me an SEO content
strategy to build topic support for
roofer Chesterfield, Missouri. make sure
that all of the pages that we're going
to build around this are to build topic
authority for this one specific
location. So that's what I would say
inside of the AI. Then the AI will
assess look at all those topics and
it'll basically take those seeds that I
just talked about. So the seeds here and
will convert those extreme relevance for
Chesterfield. Okay? So hail damage
Chesterfield, storm damage repair in
Chesterfield, so on and so forth. Okay?
Then what you can do is you can take
those ideas what the AI spits out and
then you go into claude and you'll see
here at the bottom all I did was I said
create a visual representation of this
topic map. Okay, so I just want to
visually see that topic map and you can
see this is what it produced. So this is
exactly what you would want to
implement. Okay. So, you get that
visual, nice, beautiful topic map. And
this is exactly what you want to see.
You've got the pillar page. You call
money page, whatever you want. This is
that core topic. Then from there, you're
going to start to attack those other
critical pages that need to be built out
with different intent. So, roof
inspection, replacement. The key here is
like one of the biggest questions, I've
probably gotten this question thousands
of times at this point, which is like
when do I create a new page versus when
do I target this keyword on the same
page? If the page has different intent,
you can build a new page. So, for
example, roofer Chesterfield, Missouri
is very broad. It's ambiguous. Do they
have a does their roof need to be
repaired? Do they got hail damage? Is it
an emergency repair? There's so many
unknowns just with that topic. But when
you get into these other ones, it starts
to become very clear what the intent is
behind that search. So, an example is
here, roof repair. Okay, that's
someone's not asking for a brand new
roof. They just need to get a repair
specifically like this one here just
inspection. They just want to know a
little bit of information about what's
going on. Okay, so this is really
important because this isn't just about
SEO. It's also thinking about, okay, now
that the intent is clear, now I can
build a page that's actually built to
convert. I can get really focused in on
that one problem and prove why we're the
best solution to that problem on that
page. Okay, so this is the advantage. So
what you can see here is you got those
kind of like tier one, tier two, tier
three, and so on and so forth. But once
again, another way that you can use
Claude to visualize your strategy. Okay?
And that's what I like to do. I like to
visually see, okay, I see it now. Let's
go and attack. Okay? And all this means
is basically everything I just
previously showed you as far as building
out the copy, building out the
prototype, I would just repeat that same
process, but with each of these unique
topics. Just rinse and repeat and cover
this. And the end result of this, if you
look at this, we got maybe let's say 5 6
7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15. So even with
the selected ones, that's 15 supporting
pages around Chesterfield specifically.
So we go from 1 to 15. So very simply,
it's almost impossible to not see
performance gains by doing that. And
will most businesses do that? The answer
is no. Okay, I've just worked with so
many business. I've worked in so many
agencies working with client campaigns.
No one goes this deep and they're
losing. That's why you lose because you
don't go this deep. You need to go
extreme. I'm saying extreme on these
topics. It's not there's so much
opportunity to build topics of support.
If I was working on this campaign, I
wouldn't even be thinking about any city
until I've hit at least probably 25 to
30 different topics around that one. And
then once I feel like, okay, I feel like
we've covered this pretty hard. Let's
shift into an adjacent city, like very
close. So that way, we're still keeping
that relevance tie, but now we're
building that cluster to support that
one we just hit. But people go way too
light on this. You've got to really go
aggressive and go a mile deep on each
cluster. Okay, so we got that part. Last
part here is assessing off-site. Okay,
when you think about trying to create
pages that rank everywhere, we're
talking across every single platform,
you have to you can do everything I've
described, perfect page, perfect topic
support, but if your website has no
external signals, it is not trusted and
trust comes externally. Trust does not
come from just your website. Your
website is you talking about yourself.
Therefore, it's not going to do a whole
lot. So, we need to get external
validation that we're legit, that we're
a good roofing company. Okay? And
there's two things you want to focus in
on. So, first one is let's go over to
back to the tracker. Let's see here. Go
back to this little report here. This is
the easiest thing in the world that you
can do. Okay? Go into a report, go to
citations. You can do this manually,
too. Just go into AI platforms, run
these queries, extract the citations.
You can do that. But you can just go in
here and you can export these. But I'll
show you what I'm looking for in this is
I'm looking for opportunities.
Competitors are not opportunities. So
obviously I'm not going to pay attention
to them. But what I do is I'll show you
right here is all of these ideas were
extracted from that one report. So what
I would do is I would take all of those
topics like first I'd take this one and
I'd extract those citations. Then I
would I'd run the same query through a
tracker and I'd extract the citations
there. And I would repeat this for
probably at least 10 unique topics. And
that way I've got a nice diverse pool of
citations. From there, what you'll start
to see is some commonalities of the
websites keep showing up over and over
and over. That is where you need to have
presence. And so when we look at this,
you'll see that just in that one report,
look at all these opportunities that I
found that we can today go and attack to
build topics or to build external
support for this brand. Okay, so all the
usual suspects, but there's also
Facebook and Tik Tok showing up in here,
which means okay, we got to go and
attack these directories. This would be
like a partnership. So all the
directories goes without saying, we
build a profile there. We focus on
getting some reviews populated on those
profiles and we optimize those profiles
specifically for Chesterfield. You want
to mention Chesterfield on those
profiles. Doesn't mean the whole profile
needs built around Chesterfield. You at
least need to make sure that
Chesterfield is being mentioned. That
entity is being mentioned on those
profiles. So that way, once again, we're
now we're getting external proof that we
service Chesterfield, right? And so
anyone can go and sign up for these. So
what would be the reason to not do it?
you just need to go and do this. This is
very important. So, this is where I
would spend the initial, let's call it
off-site work would be all on these
directories. I wouldn't do anything else
until I've got these all squared away.
Once these are all squared away and
we've got some review diversity coming
into these profiles, then we would focus
in probably on the social. So, Facebook,
Tik Tok, clearly they're showing up in
retrieval. So, let's start having a
presence there specifically for roofing
in Chesterville, Missouri. Once again,
you can literally take these same exact
topics and cover these same exact topics
specifically in Chesterfield, on Tik
Tok, on LinkedIn, on YouTube. It's wide
open. I'm telling you, none of no local
businesses do this. It's so wide open.
It's so easy. You could dominate so
quickly across every single search
service if you just attack the same
exact topics, but in a new format, in a
new medium, in a new channel. It just
works. Okay, now let's go back here.
Once you've tackled all the AI citations
and all the common sources of retrieval,
the next thing is you want to start to
build more authority in Chesterfield,
Missouri, specifically with Chesterfield
entities. Okay, so what does that mean?
You just go and run a prospecting report
and you So my favorite is to look for
local sponsorships. It's the easiest
thing in the world to get these. Okay,
little bit of budget. Treat it as an
advertising cost. Go and get placements
on these pages. Okay? Because these are
trusted entities in that location. These
are trusted entities where you need to
have visibility. So that's what you need
to be thinking about is how do we get
the trust? How do we get that visibility
specifically in Chesterfield? And you do
it by getting placements on the entities
that already have trust in that area.
That's it. So do whatever it takes to
get it. And that's how you're going to
build that proper external validation
for that one location so you can
actually win there. So, hope that helps.
I'll see you next video.